插曲： 「Beautiful」 by Christina Aguilera
* To all your friends, you're delirious *
* So consumed *
* In all your doom *
* Tryin' hard to fill your emptiness *
* The breeze is gone *
-十分鐘警告  -我好了
- 10-minute warning. - I'm fine.
-你的藥呢  -帶了  媽媽
- What about your meds? - Got 'em, Mom.
* 'Cause you are beautiful No matter what they say *
* 'Cause words can't bring you down *
□
豪
斯
醫
生
□
第二季 第二集
翻譯
Silmar
時
間
軸
波
多
大
叔
時間軸
波多大叔
后
期
魚
骨
頭
后期
魚骨頭
校對 Silmar
醫顧
夕橙橙   小shy
特
效
草
特效
草草
總監
Silmar
■
本字幕由人人影視字幕組翻譯
禁止用作任何商業盈利行為
豪斯
House!
-需要你  -沒門  我要回家
- Need you. - Uh-uh, forget it. I'm going home.
花粉病
Hay fever?
老天  你這么懂一定是個醫生
Boy, you must be a doctor and everything.
就兩分鐘
Two minutes.
不  病例上那個紫東西
No, the purple thingy on
說明這位神秘來客  是你的患者
the file means that "whoever" is one of yours.
也就是癌癥患者  說明絕不可能只要兩分鐘
Which means cancer, which means no way it's two minutes.
好吧  我說謊了  三十分鐘
Fine, I'm lying. 30 minutes.
生命的奧秘啊
Mystery of life.
苯海拉明或許有用
Benadryl might help.
我已經用了  一千毫克
I already did. 1,000 milligrams.
蒸汽室呢[緩解花粉病癥狀的一種方法]
Steam room?
為什么啊  吉米
Why, Jimmy!
我們早上再談
We'll talk about this in the morning.
我有個九歲的癌癥患者
I got a nine-year-old with cancer.
腺泡狀橫紋肌肉瘤
Alveolar Rhabdomyosarcoma.
絕癥患兒完勝你的鼻塞
Terminal kid trumps your stuffy nose.
還沒有
Not yet.
她出現了幻覺
She's hallucinating.
橫紋肌肉瘤擴散到大腦
So the Rhabdo's in her brain
讓她舒服些  她還有大約一周時間
make her comfortable. She's got about a week.
說得好  只是她腦部沒有癌細胞
Yeah, except there is no cancer in her brain.
CT  血檢  蛋白標志  全部陰性
Pristine CT scan, blood tests, protein markers--all negative.
癌癥在緩解
The cancer's in remission?
那么幻覺與癌癥無關
This means the hallucinations are unconnected.
引人入勝吧
Fascinating, huh?
而且  雖然不算什么大事
And, not that it matters,
如果你能治好她腦袋里的問題
but if you fix whatever's going on in her head,
就能幫她爭取一年時間
you give her maybe another year.
對九歲孩子來說很長了
A long time for a nine-year-old.
不
No.
一年轉瞬即逝
It'll just fly by.
五次大手術  一次骨髓移植
Five major surgeries, a bone marrow transplant,
十四輪化療  一次放療
14 rounds of chemo and blast radiation.
換做是我  寧可在家看看電視什么的
It was me, I'd just stay home and watch TV or something.
也不躺在顯微鏡下遭罪
Not lie here under a microscope.
別擔心
Ahh. Don't worry.
假如你遭病遭災  沒人會伸手的
Anything happens to you, nobody's gonna lift a finger.
鑒別診斷
Differential diagnosis.
各就各位  預備...
On your marks, get set...
幻覺的可能誘因...
Hallucinations could be caused...
喂
Whoa!
等我口令
Wait for it.
開始
And go.
化療造成的潛伏性神經中毒
Latent neurotoxicity from the chemo treatments.
不  患者上一次化療是兩個月前
No. Patient's last round of chemo was two months ago...
癥狀早該出現了
we would have seen it by now.
遺傳病
Genetic component?
母親沒有病史  父親在母親懷孕時跑了
Nah, nothing on mom. Dad split when she was pregnant.
同樣沒有病史
His medical history is also clean.
好一個渣男
What a guy.
有沒有可能是骨髓移植的
What about graft versus host disease
抗宿主反應
from the bone marrow transplant?
感染擴散到大腦  她出現幻覺
Infection travels to her brain, she has hallucinations.
血檢和腰椎穿刺都無異常
Blood work and LP were clean.
但如果有感染  就會有腦膜積水
But where there's infection, there's meningeal swelling.
CT上看不出腦膜異常
That CT shows no meningeal involvement.
沒錯  做毒物篩檢和核磁共振
True. Get a tox screen and an MRI.
可以  假如你想忽略剛剛的討論
We can do that, if you want to ignore what we just discussed.
好主意呀
Sounds good.
毒物接觸時間上說不通
Toxic exposure doesn't make any chronological sense.
還有第三種可能
Guess there is a third option.
幻覺是她瞎編的
She's making it all up, 'cause she
因為她打碎了鏡子不想挨訓
doesn't want to get in trouble for breaking a mirror.
不幸的是  這一可能無法檢測  所以...
Unfortunately, we can't test for that. So...
做毒物篩檢  核磁共振
tox screen, MRI,
你  遠離患者
and you stay away from the patient.
我做了什么
What'd I do?
因為面對奄奄一息的小女孩
Oh, well, you'll just get
你會愛心泛濫  自我沉淪
all warm and cuddly around the dying girl, insinuate yourself,
說不好還鬧到去爭奪監護權
probably end up in a custody battle.
奇斯  你去告訴她母親
Chase, you handle the mom.
如果病的是自己  你會回家看電視等死
Tell her that you'd just sit home and watch TV and die,
但你還是鼓足勁頭
but you had to go through the
盡力挽救她女兒的生命
motions of trying to save her daughter's life.
我們醫生就是這樣
It's a doctor thing.
這是什么鬼玩意兒
What the hell is this?
黑胡桃姜茶
Black walnut and ginger.
真好喝
It's nice.
來  躺下  我給你帶上這個小東西
Let's lay you down, and I'll attach this thingamajiggy.
-血氧監測器  -專業
- SAT monitor. - Oh, a pro.
什么都不必解釋
Don't have to explain anything.
我喜歡
I like it.
化療的中央靜脈管
Central line for the chemo.
對  不疼吧
Yeah, doesn't hurt or anything, does it?
不疼  棒極了
No, it's awesome.
輸液時幫我少挨好多針  省下好多時間
Instead of an IV, saves me a lot of time and a bunch of needle sticks.
我還從沒聽過有人說
I don't think I've ever heard
喜歡自己身上的中央靜脈管
anyone say they like their central line before.
要不要我帶你漫步公園
Right, can I interest you in a walk in the park?
-不用  謝謝  -好吧
- No, thanks. - Okay.
也不想要蝴蝶
Don't want any butterflies either.
墻壁什么樣子都無所謂
Doesn't matter what the walls look like.
你還是在找癌瘤
You're still looking for cancer.
今天不是  我們在找一處感染
Not today. We're looking for an infection.
但我懂你意思了
But I get your point.
-還舒服嗎  -嗯
- You comfortable? - Yep.
好  我們早開始早結束
All right. Let's get this over with.
專業  我喜歡
A pro. I like it.
誒呀  瞧瞧幾點了
Whoa! Look at the time.
我二十分鐘前就該閃人了
I should have been out of here 20 minutes ago.
你二十分鐘前才到
You've only been here 20 minutes.
什么都逃不過你的眼啊
Oh, can't slip anything by you, can I?
-一號問診室有患者  -我要請病假
- It's a patient in one. - I'm taking a sick day.
吃點兒氯雷他定
Take some Claritin.
突然間人人都是醫生啦
Everyone's a doctor, suddenly.
一號問診室的患者要求男醫生
Patient in one requested a male doctor.
球到你的半場了  醫生
Balls are in your court, doctor.
公會規定
Union rules.
午飯時間已近
I can't check out this
我不可以觀瞻這家伙的滲透淋病
guy's seeping gonorrhea this close to lunch.
一號問診室
Exam room one.
這是性別歧視  也是一個非常危險的開端
It's sexist, and a verydangerous precedent.
如果讓人們自由選擇醫生的性別
People could to choose the sex of their doctors,
你們女生就要沒生意啦
you gals would be out of business.
一號問診室
Exam room one.
喉嚨痛
Sore throat?
顯然不是狼瘡
That's not lupus.
拉鏈可不是隨便什么人都能操作的
Well, not everyone can operate a zipper.
拉上拉下都是功夫  還有什么來著
You know, the up, the down. What comes next?
我的新女友
My new girlfriend...
她沒交過不割包皮的男朋友
Never been with a guy who wasn't...c-circumcised.
她反應激烈  然后...
So she freaked and...
然后你就想效仿以撒討利百加歡心[圣經故事]
Aha. And you wanted Rivkah to feel all gemutlicht.
我懂  這事怪難為情的
I get it. It's a shandah.
我手頭有幾把開箱刀  于是...
I got some box cutters and, um...
亞伯拉罕也是這么干的
Just like Abraham did it.
我消過毒的...
I sterilized them. Which, uh...
-我聽說你特...  -別說了
- I was told you're sup... - Stop talking.
我去找整形外科醫生
I'm gonna get a plastic surgeon.
把你的小蛋糕塞回紙杯里
Get the Twinkie backin the wrapper.
豪斯
House.
Hey, House.
安迪的核磁共振和毒物篩檢都沒有發現
Andie's MRI and tox screen were clean.
沒有感染  沒有神經毒素
No infection, no neurotoxins.
血氧飽和94%  檢查她的心臟
Oxygen saturation is 94%. Check her heart.
她的血氧飽和正常
Her oxygen saturation is normal.
降了一個百分點
It's off by one percentage point.
在正常范圍  正常
It's within range. It's normal.
如果DNA偏差百分之一  她就是條海豚了
If her DNA was off by one percentage point, she'd be a dolphin.
我們的患者  毫無明顯誘因地出現了幻覺
We've got a patient who, for no obvious reason, is hallucinating.
既然問題不明顯  我決定著眼細微處
Since it's not obvious, I thought we'd go with subtle.
那也沒關聯  即便血氧飽和真的低
It doesn't matter. If her SAT percentage is off,
也只說明她的血液得不到充足的氧
that means her blood isn't getting enough oxygen.
那是肺有問題  不是心臟
That's a problem with her lungs, not her heart.
肺病不會引起幻覺
And a lung problem isn't causing hallucinations.
但肺部病變可能誘發其它引起幻覺的病變
But the lungs could lead to somewhere that is.
歡迎來到我推理思路的終點
Welcome to the end of the thought process.
原發性肺動脈高壓
Primary pulmonary hypertension?
可能是心包積液或者肺纖維化
Maybe PE or pulmonary fibrosis.
可能是脊椎后側凸的奇特情況
Maybe some bizarre case of kyphoscoliosis.
我要回家了
I'm going home.
趁我休息的時候  你們查一下動脈含氧量
While I'm resting, you guys get some arterial blood gases.
一旦確認她缺氧
Once you confirm that she is hypoxic,
安排肺功能體積描記  拍胸片
I want a plethysmorgraphy, chest X-ray,
做CT  通氣/灌注顯像
CT, and VQ.
如果所有檢查全沒發現
And if all that comes back negative, then
給她插肺導管
sneak a catheter into her lungs.
別擔心  我不會睡過頭  我會帶面包圈
And don't worry... I don't sleep in. I'll get bagels.
你之前做過這項檢查嗎
You ever had this test before?
查什么的
What's it for?
這個...從髖部血管進入你的肺
This...goes all the way up the vein by your hip into your lung.
如果找到什么阻塞物
If I find something up there blocking anything,
就把它拉出來  很簡單的
I pull it out...simple.
會很輕松的
It's gonna be easy.
斯隆的醫生說我的動脈很棒
The doctor at Sloan told me I had a great aorta.
你做過這項檢查
Oh, you have had this test before.
對不起  我只是喜歡聽你說話
Sorry. I just like hearing you talk.
我從沒吻過男生
I've never kissed a boy.
會有機會的
There's time yet for that.
去年夏天我遇到一個男生
There was a boy last summer.
癌癥夏令營認識的
I was at one of those cancer camps.
我一直沒勇氣問他
I just never had the guts to ask him.
你知道  我很可能...
You know, there's a good chance...
不能活著走出這家醫院了
I'm not gonna walk out of this hospital.
就算我能  我也才九歲
Even if I do, I'm nine.
三年級不太有人接吻
Not a lot of kissing going on in the third grade.
你會走出去的
You will walk out of here, all right?
你會親吻男生
And you will kiss a boy.
這就對了
There you go.
笑一笑
Smile.
能親我一下嗎
Will you kiss me?
不行
No.
沒人會知道的
No one will ever know.
我...對不起
I'm...I'm...I'm sorry.
我不能
I can't.
我不會告訴別人的
I won't tell anyone.
聽我說  你才九歲
Listen, you're nine years old.
我三十了
I'm 30.
我只是想知道那是什么感覺
I just want to know what it feels like.
就一次
Once.
這不是你最后的機會
This isn't your last chance for that.
如果是呢
What if it is?
求你親我一下
Please kiss me.
面包圈
Bagels.
你沒睡過頭
You didn't sleep in.
沒睡著  沒喘氣  我要死了
Didn't sleep. Didn't breathe. I'm dying.
安迪的肺動脈造影沒有異常
Pulmonary angiogram of Andie's lungs was clean.
動脈血氣分析和CT也正常
Arterial blood gases and CT scan were also normal.
她的心肺沒有問題
Her heart and lungs are fine.
所以我們仍然無法解釋血氧飽和降低
Which gives us no explanation for the diminished SAT percentage.
是啊  說來奇怪  有時候正常就是正常
Yeah, oddly enough, sometimes normal is normal.
有時候我們看不出正常為何不正常
Sometimes we can't see why normal isn't normal.
把她的癥狀寫在白板上
Get her symptoms on the board.
竟然準我用馬克筆了
Whoa, you're letting me touch the markers?
我的事前醫療護理指示里寫著
It's written down in my advanced health care directive.
假如我發生任何形式的能力喪失
Should I be incapacitated in any way,
白板由你負責  你之后是福曼
you run the board, then Foreman.
奇斯  你還沒準備好
Chase, you're just not ready yet.
還有什么
What else?
各位  我知道我們大致排除了感染
Guys, I know we sort of ruled out infection, but...
但先將檢測結果放在一邊
if we forget the labs for a minute,
還有一項檢測我們因為她的年齡原因沒有做
there is one infection we didn't test for because of her age:
神經梅毒
neurosyphylis.
不可能
There's no way.
如果感染浸入她的大腦皮層
If the infection dipped into her cerebral cortex,
所有周圍神經功能都會受到影響
all peripheral functions could be compromised.
不  她沒有性經歷  她才九歲
No, she hasn't had sex. She's nine.
或許她不是主動的
Maybe it wasn't her idea.
她身邊成年人很多
I mean, she's been around a lot of adults.
總進醫院  癌癥夏令營的指導員
All the hospital visits, the counselors at the cancer camps.
你認為她被猥褻過
You think she's been molested?
如果真有  她可隱藏的太好了
Hiding it pretty well if there's any of that going on.
對呀  遭猥褻的女孩都喜歡把這事掛在嘴上
Yeah, all girls who have been molested want to talk about it.
去查強奸證據
Break out the rape kit.
她沒有性經歷
She hasn't had sex.
你為何如此肯定
Why are you so sure?
她說她從沒吻過男生
She told me she'd never kissed a boy.
你還讀了她的日記
You read her diary too?
她求我吻她
She asked me to...kiss her.
"我的陳述完畢"
I rest my case.
普通九歲女孩不會分分鐘想著性
A regular nine-year-old girl does not have sex on the brain.
尤其是醫生往她血管里穿導管的時候
Not when a doctor's threading a catheter through her veins.
她不是普通的九歲孩子
Well, she's not a regular nine-year-old.
她癌癥晚期
She's got terminal cancer.
得癌癥不能讓人變得特別
Cancer doesn't make you special.
而猥褻行為...
Molestation, on the other hand...
她只求死前能有個吻
She wanted one kiss before she dies.
她連男生都沒親過  猜她沒有性經歷就很合理
If she's never kissed a boy, it's a fair bet she's never had sex.
去跟那些不肯吻我嘴的妓女說吧
Tell that to all the hookers who won't kiss me on the mouth.
推測如下
Hey, here's a theory.
她遭遇過猥褻
She has been molested,
在浪漫幻想中尋求安慰
seeks refuge in romantic
心儀發型閃亮的年長帥哥
fantasies with older men with great hair,
而且你漏掉了最關鍵的部分
and I think you left out the punch line.
猥褻受害者懂得見縫插針
Victims of molestation learn to work the angles.
最會操縱人
Manipulate people.
你真的照做了  是不是
You did it, didn't you?
你吻了她
You kissed her.
這不是病態  只是給臨終的女孩一個吻
It-it wasn't sick. It was one kiss for a dying girl.
小小的...
One small...
小小的死前一吻  謝謝
One small kiss before she dies. Thank you.
所以才不讓你動我的馬克筆
This is exactly why you can't touch my markers.
-去查她有沒有性經歷  -好
- Go see if she's had sex. - Okay.
沒人碰過我
No one's ever touched me.
只是需要確認一下
We just need to be sure.
我喜歡你的頭發
I like your hair.
以前我的頭發特別多卷
I used to have really curly hair.
我一直希望能有你這樣的頭發
I always wanted it to be like yours is.
謝謝
Thank you.
好了
All right.
結束了
That's it.
你沒事
You're fine.
我有患者
With a patient.
她快死了嗎
She dying?
沒
No.
那她可以等
Then she can wait.
可以等我兩分鐘嗎
Will you excuse me just two minutes?
她要是被猥褻過
If only she'd been molested.
我們還有的可查
Then we'd have something to go on.
無暴力闖入痕跡
No forced entry.
一次幻覺
One hallucination.
或許只是吃了變質肉  或許沒什么特別
Maybe it was just...bad pork. Maybe there's nothing...
她狀態不對
She's not fine.
血氧飽和又下降一個百分點
Her SAT percentage dropped another point.
可能說明她的肺部有腫瘤
Which could suggest a tumor in her lung.
肺病不能解釋幻覺問題
Lung wouldn't explain the hallucination.
CT顯示雙肺正常
CT scan showed both lungs were clean.
那么她心臟有腫瘤
Which means there's a tumor in her heart.
不可能  給我
Not a chance. Give me that.
是我擰松的
I loosened it.
我擰開的
I opened it.
心臟做過核磁共振和回聲探測  沒有異常
We've got an MRI and an echo of her heart. There's nothing there.
再想一個理論
Give me one other explanation...
解釋血氧飽和低
for low oxygen saturation.
想不出
I can't.
只有一種情況
There's only one condition that
同時影響心臟和大腦
simultaneously affects the heart and the brain,
-可是她...  -好極了  就照這個來
- but she... - Perfect. Let's go with that.
腺泡狀橫紋肌肉瘤患兒
Tuberous Sclerosis in a
又得了結節性硬化癥
kid that also has Alveolar Rhabdomyosarcoma?
同時患上兩種完全不相關的癌癥
Two different, unrelated cancers
統計學上完全不可能
at the same time is a statistical no-no.
一般人群中的癌癥發病率是多少
What's the rate of cancer in the general population?
萬分之一
One in 10,000?
別...別玩數字
Don't...don't start with the numbers.
我猜想  一萬個癌癥患者中
The way I figure it, one in
會有一個罹患另一種癌癥
10,000 of them should have another cancer.
小姑娘中了兩次彩票
Little girl won the lottery twice.
這也是有的
It happens.
那你要給她開刀
So you're gonna cut her open?
探查手術
Exploratory surgery.
必須找到這東西
Gotta find this thing.
你打算用內窺鏡胡亂探查一個
You're just gonna grope around
免疫系統受損的九歲孩子
inside an immuno-compromised nine-year-old?
她會死在手術臺上的
She could die on the table.
我知道一定在心臟附近
I know it's somewhere near the heart.
豪斯
House...
你得拿出更好的辦法
You've gotta do better than that.
我們來這做什么
Why are we here?
音效更贊
Better acoustics.
聽聽這個
Now listen to this.
這是二尖瓣
That's a mitral heart valve.
錯  掏掏耳朵
No, get the wax out of your ears.
這是患者的主動脈瓣
This is the patient's aortic valve.
我下載了她的超聲波心動
I downloaded the audio of her echocardiogram.
我們這是在聽什么
What are we trying to hear?
腫瘤
Tumor.
腫瘤都很安靜  因為它們沒嘴
They tend to keep quiet on account of them not having any mouths.
但是我們可以在瓣膜回聲中聽出異常
But we could hear an abnormality in the sound of the valve.
回聲異常暗示異物的存在
Which would indicate the presence of something.
比如說  腫瘤
The tumor, for example.
如果我們能告訴外科醫生到哪里去找腫瘤
If we can tell a surgeon where to look,
那就不是探查手術  是精準打擊
this is no longeran exploratory surgery. It's a precision strike.
主動脈瓣聽起來很正常
Her aortic valve sounds normal.
太糟了
Too bad.
來聽聽安迪三尖瓣的美妙旋律
Now listen to the dulcet tones of Andie's tricuspid valve.
-正常  -這
- Normal. - And this...
是她的二尖瓣
is her mitral valve.
我沒聽出什么異常
I don't hear anything weird.
你們真令我哀傷
Oh, you guys make me sad.
再聽
Listen again.
她不過出現一次幻覺  我們干嘛要動手術
She's had one hallucination. Why are we operating on her?
為什么拿她的生命冒險
Why are we risking her life?
因為威爾森認為
Because Wilson thinks it'd be nice
給小姑娘一年時間跟媽媽說再見是件好事
to give the girl a year to say good-bye to her mommy.
可能她結巴或者怎么的
Guess maybe she stutters or something.
閉嘴仔細聽
Now shut up and listen.
三尖瓣
Tricuspid.
二尖瓣
Mitral.
再來
Again.
等等
Wait.
這里
There.
多出一拍
There's an extra flap.
我讓外科醫生先查二尖瓣
I'm gonna ask a surgeon to look at the mitral valve first.
奇斯  你也去
Chase, I want you there.
我不喜歡讀外科醫生的報告  特別無趣
I don't like reading surgeons' reports. They're boring.
我不確定我該不該再...
I'm not really sure I should be spending more time...
手術中她會不省人事
She'll be unconscious.
你是安全的
You'll be safe.
你醒來的時候我會在的
I'll be there when you wake up.
我不會有事的  媽媽
I'm gonna be fine, mom.
勇敢的孩子
Brave kid.
反過來安慰她媽媽
She even gave her mom a pep talk.
成熟  勇敢  她真是個奇跡
Mature, brave. She's a wonder.
你怎么回事
What's your problem?
這些癌癥患兒  你不能把他們全捧上神壇
These cancer kids. You can't put them all on a pedestal.
從基本的統計學上講
It's basic statistics.
其中必定有些人膽小如弗萊迪貓[動畫]
Some of them have got to be whiny little fraidy-cats.
你真不可理喻
You're unbelievable.
如果群體中一個膽小鬼都沒有  那么...
If there's not one yellow belly in the whole group, then...
勇敢也就毫無意義了
being brave doesn't have any meaning.
安迪優雅地面對絕境
Andie handles an impossible situation with grace.
這不值得欣賞嗎
That's not to be admired?
你看到優雅是因為你想看到優雅
You see grace because you want to see grace.
你看不到優雅是因為你都不去看她
You don't see grace because you won't go anywhere near her.
你們這些人迷戀偶像崇拜到了病態的地步
Idolizing is pathological with you people.
你們從一無可取之處看到欣賞對象
You see things to admire where there's nothing.
是啊  我們太邪惡了
Yeah, well,we're evil.
本該不屑的東西  你也欣賞得起來
You find things to admire where you shouldn't be sniffing at all.
比如會計部的黛比
Like Debbie in accounting.
她...很好啊
She's...nice.
你不該知道  你已經結婚了
You shouldn't know that. You're married.
小姑娘得癌癥快死了  我不應該喜歡她嗎
So the little kid dying of cancer, I shouldn't like her?
要是你快死了  全世界都會突然愛上你
If you're dying, suddenly everybody loves you.
你還拄拐呢  連個喜歡你的都沒有
You have a cane. Nobody even likes you.
我又沒得絕癥  我只是可悲
I'm not terminal. I'm merely pathetic.
我做下爛事不挨罵的時候多著呢  說出來你都不信
You wouldn't believe the crap people let me get away with.
他們找到腫瘤了
They found a tumor.
在肺部  發展到心臟
It's in her lung, extending into her heart.
核磁共振成像上看不到
It wasn't visible on the MRI
因為它沿著心壁生長
because it's growing along the heart wall.
因為腫瘤位置特殊
Now, because of the placement,
外科醫生只能暫時取出安迪的心臟
the surgeon has to temporarily remove Andie's heart.
這叫做外植
It's called an explant.
他們切除腫瘤
They cut out the tumor,
用牛心包補片取代受損的心肌
replace any damaged heart muscle with bovine patches.
是從牛的心包膜上取的
That's a patch made from a cow's pericardium.
就是包裹心臟的包膜
It's a sac that encloses the heart.
她的存活幾率有多大
What are her chances?
問題在于  切除全部腫瘤之后
The problem is there might not be enough heart left
剩余的心臟組織可能不夠
once they remove all of the tumor.
而且如果腫瘤已經轉移
And if the tumor's metastasized,
我們就無能為力了
there's nothing we can do.
墨菲醫生
Dr. Murphy.
等我打好這個結
Just let me tie this off.
-醫生  -怎么了
- Doctor. - What?
她眼內有出血
She's got a bleed in her eye.
找到了腫瘤  修復了心臟
They got a tumor, repaired her heart,
她卻眼底出血了
but she bled out of her eye.
眼內出血不是心臟腫瘤引起的
She didn't bleed out of her eye from a heart tumor.
沒錯  心臟腫瘤是良性的
True. The cardiac tumor was benign.
-這不可能  -統計學上講...
- It's impossible. - Statistically...
閉嘴  如果腫瘤是良性的
Oh, shut up. If the tumor's benign,
幻覺就不是這個腫瘤引發的
that means it didn't cause her hallucinations.
所以我才提出來
That's why I'm mentioning it.
所以腫瘤只是個巧合
So the tumoris a coincidence.
糟糕  你都開始闡述顯然的事實了
This is bad. You're starting to state the obvious.
不  你說那里有腫瘤  那里果然有腫瘤
No, you said it would be there. It was there.
這不可能是巧合
It can't be a coincidence.
癌癥晚期的九歲孩子
A nine-year-old with terminal cancer
心臟有顆毫無關聯的良性腫瘤  為什么
gets an unrelated benign tumor growing in her heart...why?
良性的  不可能
It's benign? That's impossible.
你問威爾森
Talk to Wilson.
視網膜出血呢  另一個巧合嗎
And the retinal bleed... another coincidence?
血栓可能增加眼底壓力  導致出血
A clot could create pressure behind the eye, cause the bleeding.
血栓可以解釋眼部癥狀
A clot could explain the eye,
但不能解釋幻覺
but doesn't explain the hallucinations.
血栓可能引起癲癇小發作
A clot could cause mini-seizures.
好極了  又一個不會引發幻覺的東西
Great, another thing that's not causing hallucinations.
癲癇后精神障礙
Post-seizure psychosis.
癲癇發作后大腦制造幻覺來自我糾正
The brain sort of corrects itself after the seizure by hallucinating.
血栓可以解釋眼內出血和幻覺
The clot could explain the eye and the hallucinations.
但是腫瘤呢
But what about the tumor?
章魚大小的腫瘤包裹著小女孩的心臟
Tumors the size of an octopus wrapped around a little girl's heart
不可能只是巧合
are not just a coincidence.
她并不健康  從未健康過
She's not healthy. She's never been healthy.
什么理論  這女孩的身體是顆檸檬
What's the theory here? This girl's body's a lemon?
故障集合體  所有部件分崩離析
Faulty manufacturing? Everything's falling apart?
腫瘤是阿富汗
The tumor is Afghanistan.
血栓是水牛城
The clot is Buffalo.
還需要進一步解釋嗎
Does that need more explanation?
好吧  腫瘤是基地組織
Okay, the tumor is Al Qaeda.
大壞蛋  核心成員  我們沖進去消滅了它
The big bad guy, the brains. We went in, wiped it out.
但它已經派出一隊"分裂細胞"[游戲]
But it had already sent out a Splinter Cell.
一伙低級恐怖分子
A small team of low-level terrorists
悄悄潛伏在水牛城  伺機將我們一網打盡
quietly living in some suburb of Buffalo, waiting to kill us all.
你是想說  在我們切除它之前
Are you trying to say that
腫瘤拋出了一個血栓
the tumor threw a clot before we removed it?
多么精妙的比喻
It was an excellent metaphor.
在血栓引爆自殺炸彈前給她做腦血管照影
Angio her brain before this clot straps on an explosive vest.
血管照影正常
Angio was clean.
沒有血栓
There's no clot?
有血栓  只是我們找不到
There's a clot. We just can't find it.
大腦不能做探查手術
We can't do exploratory surgery on her brain.
你確定自己不是神經學專家
Are you sure you're not a neurologist?
好吧
Okay.
她要死了
She's gonna die.
血栓不會悄悄消失
Well, the clot's not gonna go away quietly.
隨時可能爆炸
It could blow at any time.
你要去通知她們嗎
Are you gonna let them know?
我想是的
I guess so.
能陪你去嗎
Can I come with?
去告訴安迪她要死了
To tell Andie she's gonna die?
相當不像你
That's very un-you.
她如此勇敢
Well, she's such a brave girl.
我想看她聽說自己就快死了時有多勇敢
I want to see how brave she is when you tell her she's gonna die.
去死吧你
Go to hell.
如果聽說自己快死了  你們會怎么做
What would you do if you were told you were gonna die?
不知道  我會不知所措
I don't know. I'd be devastated.
你會哭得像個孩子
You'd cry like a baby.
是人都會那樣
Everybody would.
她什么反應都沒有
She's not doing anything.
-鐵石心腸  -她勇敢
- She's a rock. - She's brave.
沒錯  為什么
Yeah, yeah, yeah. Why?
她經歷過的打擊比大部分人一輩子還多
She's gone through more than most people do in a lifetime.
那又怎樣  那能說明她想死嗎
So what? Does that mean she's ready to die?
如果她的勇敢...是一種病征呢
What if her bravery... is a symptom?
血栓引發幻覺  擾亂她的情感
The clot is causing the hallucinations and messing with her emotions.
你認為她的勇敢是化學造成的
You think her bravery is chemically based?
這能告訴我們去哪兒找血栓
It'd tell us where to look for the clot.
恐懼中樞在哪里
Where's the fear center?
杏仁核  在海馬體附件
In the amygdala, near the hippocampus.
那區域很大  而且神經密集
It's a big area, and a busy one.
隨便開刀會害死她
You blindly cut in there, you could kill her.
你要看到血栓  只能等尸檢了
Only time you're gonna see this clot is at autopsy.
那就做尸檢吧
Then let's do that.
現在給活人做尸檢還合法嗎
Is it still illegal to perform an autopsy on a living person?
你嗑藥了嗎
Are you high?
如果今天是周二  我嗑到不知所以
If it's Tuesday, I'm wasted.
今天周三
It's Wednesday.
我想低溫誘發心臟停搏
I want to induce a hypothermic cardiac arrest.
給患者接體外循環  抽出兩升血
Once the patient's on bypass, we siphon off two liters of blood,
然后邊做磁共振掃描邊向大腦灌注
then perfuse the brain while she's in an MRI.
你這是在說殺死她
You're actually talking about killing her.
就那么一會兒  我會很快把她復活
Just for a little while. I'll bring her right back.
既然如此  放手去做好了  有什么好討論的
Oh, well, in that case, go ahead. Why are we even talking?
如果我們不作為  她一天之內就會死
If we do nothing, she's dead in a day.
或許一周
Maybe a week.
這是往長了說
The kind that lasts.
用于診斷目的手術
We need FDA approval for any surgical technique
-需要FDA的許可  -當然
- that's used for diagnostic purposes. - Absolutely,
入侵性手術需要許可
if we were doing anything invasive.
但我的手術沒有入侵性
But there's nothing invasive...
你看  我不是給她開顱
You know, I'm not cutting into her head.
-我只是在找血栓  -還說不入侵
- I'm just looking for a clot. - Not invasive?
你會殺了她的
You're killing her.
別揪著細節不放  如果成功  她就活了
Don't split hairs. If it works, she lives.
務必讓她母親明白  只有百萬分之一的成功率
Make sure the mom understands that this is a million-to-one shot.
我會監督威爾森傳達的
I'll see that Wilson passes that along.
我們的計劃...基本就是重啟你的女兒
The plan...is basically to reboot your daughter.
就像重啟電腦
Like a computer.
給她關機  然后重新啟動
We shut her down, then restart her.
怎么重啟一個九歲女孩
How do you restart a nine-year-old girl?
我們將她的體溫降到21攝氏度
We cool her core body temperature to 21 degrees Celsius.
用毯子和冰
Use blankets, ice.
像是冬眠嗎
Sort of like...hibernation?
不盡然
Not quite.
冬眠中的熊有非常緩慢的心跳
In hibernation, a bear's heartbeat is just very slow.
而心臟停搏中是沒有心跳的
In cardiac arrest, there is no heartbeat.
那她不是死了
So she's dead.
暫時來講  是的
Temporarily, yes.
通過降低她的體溫  我們能將...
By cooling her, we limit the risk of damage
抽出血液的風險降到最低
when we...remove her blood.
并不是全部  兩三升
Not all of it. Two to three liters.
她一半的血
Half her blood?
然后再輸回去
Then we put it back.
這叫做血管灌流
It's called perfusing the circuit.
我們要做的是腦部灌流
In this case, her brain.
這樣我們就能爭取到一段非常短暫的時間
And using an MRI, we'd have a very brief window
借助核磁共振  有望看到血栓的輪廓
to hopefully see the outline of the clot.
如果找到血栓并且可以手術
If it's there, and it's operable,
我們將它取出來
we go get it.
安迪就可以走出醫院了
And Andie walks out of here.
-簽好的同意書  -好極了  謝謝
- Signed consent forms. - Great, thanks.
你聽起來好多了
You sound better.
用了一大坨薄荷膏  幾粒維科丁
I stacked a combo of Mentholatum, a few Vicodin,
還有一堆什么我都不記得了
and something else which I can't remember.
應該夠我興奮個幾小時
Should be able to ride the high for a couple hours.
安迪怎么說
What did Andie say?
關于什么
About what?
-關于這個  -我沒跟她談
- About this? - I didn't talk to her.
她不需要知道手術操作的細節
She doesn't need to know the specifics of this procedure.
如果你是對的呢
What if you're right about her?
如果她真的有那么勇敢呢
What if she just is that brave?
那也不意味著她成熟到足以面對這種抉擇
That doesn't mean she's mature enough to handle this kind of decision.
除非她真能理解  否則就不是她勇敢
Either she understands, or she's not brave.
無知不是勇敢
You can't have it both ways.
如果她能理解
If she does understand,
她有權知道要發生什么
then she deserves to know what's going on.
-我是豪斯醫生  -我見過你
- I'm Dr. House. - I've seen you around.
你媽媽告訴你我們要做的事了嗎
Your mom tell you what we're gonna try?
說了個大概
Sort of.
明天的檢查可能要持續十個小時
Tomorrow's test could take 10 hours.
鑒于你目前的身體狀況  你可能撐不過去
Given your present condition, you might not even make it through.
-我媽媽查了很多材料...  -你自己怎么想
- My mom's done a lot of research. - How do you feel about it?
如果成熟取決于一個人還有多少日子可活
If we figured maturity came from how much time you've got left
而不是活過多少日子  那就該由你來做決定
instead of how long you've been here, this would be your call.
我別無選擇  不是嗎
I don't have a choice, right?
我可以給你選擇的機會
I could give you one.
我想好起來
I wanna get better.
你得的是癌癥
You've got cancer.
-要是我能治好眼下的...  -我還有一年
- If I fix this... - I have a year.
一年這樣的時光
A year of this.
很多人不會想要這樣的生活
A lot of people wouldn't want that.
很多人會只想早點兒結束
A lot of people would just want it to be over.
你是在問我想不想死嗎
Are you asking if I wanna die?
沒人想死
Nobody wants to die.
可是你就要死了
But you're going to.
問題是怎樣死去
The question is, how?
你會承受多少痛苦
How much you're gonna suffer, and
痛苦多久
how long.
我在問你想不想結束痛苦
I'm asking if you want this to be over.
那你怎么跟我媽媽說
What would you tell my mom?
我會給她十個完美的理由
I would give her 10 excellent medical reasons
解釋為何無法進行手術
why we can't do this procedure.
我不能只因為自己累了就丟下她
I can't just leave her 'cause I'm tired.
但你也不可能為她留下
But you can't stay for her, either.
可是她需要我
But she needs me here.
這是你的人生
This is your life.
你不能只為了她活著
You can't do this just for her.
我愛她
I love her.
歡迎各位參加今晚的帶妝彩排
Thank you for joining me for tonight's dress rehearsal.
飾演艾迪的是莫蒂·倫道夫
Playing the part of Andie is Morty Randolph.
我們對他為科學捐軀致以深深的謝意
For his donation to science, we give our thanks.
一旦安迪冷卻  接通體外循環
Once Andie is cooled and goes off bypass,
我們有60秒時間從她體內抽出兩升血
we have 60 seconds to get two liters of blood out of her body,
再灌注回去  目的是獲取她腦中血栓的圖像
back into her for the pictures to find the clot in her head.
如果明天核磁共振成像時有人撞到我們的明星
If our star is bumped tomorrow, while my MRI is on,
這些紅燈就會亮起
these red lights will go off.
意味著我們得不到可用的檢測結果
Which will mean we have no usable test results.
沒有可用結果  那就是《再見  百老匯》
No test results, it's goodbye Broadway.
諸位就只好去得梅因演壞貓了
You guys'll be wearing bad cat suits in Des Moines.
神經外科醫師負責盯著成像屏幕
We'll have neuro surgeons here with a view of the monitors,
心外科醫生待命  以防需要開胸
cardiac surgeon there in case we need to open her up.
兩位麻醉師  一個盯著心肺環機
Anesthesiologists: one by the cardiac bypass machine,
一個盯著冷卻器
one by the cooling apparatus.
合唱團的姑娘們  身高超過五尺十寸的跟我來
Girls in the chorus, if you're over 5'10", stick with me.
好  倒計時六十秒
Okay, give me 60 seconds on the clock.
好戲開臺
Show time.
五  六  七  八
A-five, six, seven, eight!
動脈插管抽血
Siphon off the blood through the arterial line.
嗖  抽血的聲音  嗖嗖嗖
Whoosh! Sound of blood draining. More whoosh.
現在我們...
And we...
殺了她
kill her.
再來
Again.
-抱歉  我的手...  -這能有多難
-Sorry, my hand... - How hard can this be?
-這邊有點兒忙  -再來
- It's a little busy down here. - Again.
-如果我們不必灌洗她的腸胃...  -再來
- If we didn't have to lavage her gastrointestinal... - Again.
再來
Again!
我們可以把她固定在手術臺上
We could bolt her to the table.
簡單粗暴令人發指
Gruesome and low-tech.
吻我吧  我喜歡
Kiss me, I love it.
五  六  七  八
A-five, six, seven, eight!
給  醫生
Here you go, Doctor.
這會讓你睡過去
This'll make you sleep.
好多人
A lot of people.
閨女  今兒可是音樂盛宴
Big musical number, kiddo.
這么多人都是來捧你場的
A lot of people here to make you look good.
你有點兒嚇到我了
You're kind of freaking me out.
經常有人被他嚇到
He gets that sometimes.
深呼吸  親愛的
Deep breath, honey.
好了  開始
Okay, go.
體溫37攝氏度
Body temperature 37 degrees Celsius.
開始冷卻
Start the cooling.
你  開始
You, go.
-她在顫抖  -兩百毫克維庫溴銨
- She's shivering. - 200 milligrams of vecuronium.
24攝氏度
24 degrees Celsius.
發生房顫
We have afib.
-干什么  -她死了
- What? - She's dead.
要的就是這樣
That's the whole idea.
開始
Go.
抽出一升
One liter out.
兩升
Two liters.
好  開始回灌
Okay, put the blood back in.
灌流回血管
Reperfuse the circuit.
有發現嗎  任何發現
Anything, people, anything at all.
頸內動脈海綿竇正常
Internal carotid artery in cavernous sinus is fine.
十秒
10 seconds.
前庭蝸神經完好
Vestibulocochlear nerve intact.
腦膜中動脈正常
Middle meningeal artery clear.
-五秒  -沒有
- Five seconds. - Nothing.
時限過了
We're over the limit.
必須開始給她升溫
We've got to start rewarming her,
不然會造成永久傷害
or there'll be permanent damage.
繼續找
Keep looking!
在那
There!
我什么都沒看到
I didn't see anything.
-就在那  -你確定
- It was there. - You sure?
海馬體側面四毫米  我看到了
Four millimeters lateral to the hippocampus. I saw it.
豪斯  沒時間了  她會變成植物人的
House, she's out of time. She's gonna be a vegetable.
我看到了
I saw it.
我認為可以了
That's good enough for me.
恢復心跳成功了
They were able to restart her heart.
她的狀態非常理想
She's doing as well as can be hoped.
他們找到血栓了
So they found the clot.
我們認為是的
We think so.
神經外科醫生正在試圖將它取出來
The neurosurgeons are attempting to remove it right now.
什么時候能知道有沒有造成傷害
And when will we know if there was any damage?
幾小時后
A few hours.
插曲： 「In The Deep」 by Bird York
* Thought you had *
* All the answers *
* To rest your heart upon *
* But somethin' happens*
* Don't see it coming, now *
* You can't stop yourself *
* Now you're out there *
海馬體側面四毫米
Four millimeters lateral to the hippocampus.
我就在那兒
That's where I am.
什么都沒有
There's nothing there.
你還沒到  繼續
You're not there yet. Keep going.
我已經到了
I'm there.
你確定看到了...
Are you sure you saw...
在這里
There it is.
我想我能取出來
I think I can get it.
* Life keeps tumbling *
* Your heart in circles *
* Till you let go *
* Till you shed your pride *
* And you climb to heaven *
嗨  媽媽
Hi, Mom.
* And you throw yourself off *
嗨  親愛的
Ohh, hi, baby.
* Now you're out there spinning *
* In the deep *
你治鼻塞用的是...
You're treating your stuffy nose with...
可卡因
cocaine?
* In the deep... *
苯海拉明
Diphenhydramine.
抗組胺劑  這是一種...
Antihistamine. It's a...
新傳導系統  血腦屏障什么的
new delivery system. It's a blood-brain barrier thing.
一切只為了快  是不是
It's all about speed, isn't it?
一件事接一件  從不停駐
One thing to another, never standing still.
你...很熟練啊
You're...pretty good at that.
本人精于剃刀
I know my way around a razor blade.
時間到了
It's time.
還有幾個小塊
Just a couple more rocks.
安迪要回家了
Andie's going home.
對啊
Right.
矮矬光禿小丑大巡游
The parade of the small, bald circus freaks.
抱歉  鄙人正忙
Sorry, I...got a thing.
我讀了外科醫生的報告
I read the surgeon's report.
血栓離杏核仁很遠
Clot was nowhere near her amygdala.
就是說她的恐懼情感完全正常
Means her fear emotions were working perfectly.
-是啊  -是啊
- Yeah. - Yeah.
她的勇敢不是病征
So her...bravery was not a symptom.
對
Yeah.
我錯了
I was wrong.
她真心是一位自我犧牲的圣人
She genuinely is a self-sacrificing saint,
生命帶給她的只有痛苦
whose life will bring her nothing but pain.
她堅忍地承受著這些痛苦
Which she will stoically withstand...
只為她母親能晚上一陣再傷心哭泣
just so that her mom doesn't have to cry quite so soon.
我喜不自勝
I am beside myself with joy.
她活得比你快樂
She enjoys life more than you do.
才怪
Right.
她從奇斯那里偷到一個吻
She stole that kiss from Chase.
你最近又做了什么
What have you done lately?
我又不著急
I'm pacing myself.
與她不同  我有大把時間
Unlike her, I have the luxury of time.
她會比你命長的
She could outlive you.
* In the silence *
* All your secrets *
* Raise their worried heads...*
假如你想看真蝴蝶
In case you want to see real butterflies.
* Back together...*
* Now you're out there *
* Flipping *
* In the deep *
我不會吻你的  不論你怎么說
I'm not gonna kiss you, no matter what you say.
* In the deep *
外面陽光很好
It's sunny outside.
你該出去走走
You should go for a walk.
嗯  不怎么喜歡逛公園
Yeah. Not much for the long walks in the park.
* Every day is so wonderful *
* And suddenly, it's hard to breathe *
* Now and then I get insecure*
* From all the pain, I'm so ashamed *
* I am beautiful, no matter what they say *
* Words can't bring me down *
液冷式
Liquid cooled...
* I am beautiful in every single way *
右腿嗎
Right leg?
*Yes, words can't *
什么
Huh?
*bring me down...*
你的右腿
Your right leg?
不影響騎車
You can still ride.
如今資金充裕
We got excellent financing right now.
這輛標價一萬零八百
It lists for 10,800.
給我一萬零三百  就便宜你了
I'll let you steal it out the door for 10,300.
不必  多謝
No, thanks.
可以試騎嗎
Could I test-drive one of these things?
* No matter what you do *
* No matter what we say *
* We're the songinside the tune *
* Full of beautiful mistakes *
* And everywhere we go *
* The sun will always shine *
* Tomorrow we might wake upon the other side *
* Or the other time *
* We are beautiful...*